（シー）うあっ！
《こ…　これは…　幻術か…》
I-Is this is... a genjutsu?
《こいつら　仲間の攻撃を
うまく　陽動に当ててきやがる。
These guys are cleverly using
each other's attacks to divert attention.
俺としたことが！　くそ～！》
And I fell for it. Damn it!
《体が…　動かない…》
Can't... move...
（重吾）ヒャハハハ～！
殺した！　殺してやったぜ～！
I killed him! I killed the guy!
次は　どいつだ～！
Who's next?!
♪～
（ナルト）ウソだ！　そんなの　デタラメだ！
You're lying!
That's nonsense!
（ヤマト）そんな…　まさか…。
No, it can't be.
（カカシ）冗談は　よせ。
そんな話は　信じられん。
Stop joking around.
Who'd believe that story?
（マダラ）ウソではない。
それが　イタチの真実だ。
It's not a lie. That's the truth about Itachi.
やつは　サスケのため
木ノ葉の里のために死んだ。
He died for Sasuke's sake and
for the Hidden Leaf Village.
♪～
（カカシ）どういうことだ？
What does that mean?
もし　それが事実だとしても
それを　サスケが知っているなら→
Even if it is true,
if Sasuke is aware of this,
なぜ　サスケは　暁に手を貸す？
why would he help the Akatsuki?
あいつなら　イタチの意志を継ぎ
木ノ葉へ帰ってくるはずだ。
Knowing him, he would return to
the Hidden Leaf to carry on Itachi's will.
（マダラ）フッ。
サスケの師として　友として→
As Sasuke's teacher and his friends,
お前らは　サスケの本心を→
you might have assumed you understood
Sasuke's true feelings.
わかったつもりでいたんだろうが
とんだお門違いだ。
But you were badly mistaken.
（マダラ）本物だ。
本物の復讐者だよ　彼は。
He's the real thing. A true avenger.
That's what he is.
お前が
サスケを　そんなふうにしたのか！？
Did you turn Sasuke into that?!
いや　違う。
No, I didn't.
サスケ自身が　そう選択したのさ。
Sasuke chose this himself.
そんなの…　ウソだ～！
It's a lie!
（マダラ）俺も　賭けだった。
I took a gamble too.
彼が　イタチの意志を取るか→
Would Sasuke carry
on Itachi's wishes,
はたまた
木ノ葉への復讐を取るのか。
or would he seek revenge against
the Hidden Leaf?
彼は　復讐を選んだ。
He chose vengeance.
本心は　こちら側の
人間だったということさ。
In essence, he was meant to
be on our side.
（マダラ）サスケの　今の目的…→
Sasuke's goal at this moment is to
take revenge against the Hidden Leaf
それは
うちは一族とイタチを　追い込んだ→
for what they did to Itachi
and the Uchiha Clan.
木ノ葉への復讐。
なんで…→
Why?
なんで　あいつが…。
Why him?
どうして
こんなことに　なっちまう。
Why did this happen?
どうして　復讐に向かっちまう！？
How could he turn to revenge?!
しかたないのさ。
It was inevitable.
それが
血塗られたうちはの憎しみの運命。
It is the Uchiha Clan's blood-soaked
destiny of hate.
はるか昔から　永久に続いてきた
呪いのようなものだ。
Like a curse that has been
passed down through the ages.
呪い？
そう。
A curse?
はるか昔　六道仙人と呼ばれる
忍の祖から始まる　憎しみの呪い。
Yes. A curse of hatred,
which started generations ago
with the Sage of the Six Paths who is
said to be the founder of the ninja.
六道仙人だと？
The Sage of the Six Paths?
そんなものは
ただの神話のはずだ。
That's just a myth.
輪廻眼は　突然変異にすぎないと！
The Rinnegan was
no more than a mutation!
神話は
事実に　なぞられて語られる。
Myths are born from truth.
かつて六道仙人は　忍宗を説き→
Long ago, the Sage of the Six Paths
preached the Ninshu
平和を　導こうとしたが→
and tried to lead the way to peace.
夢半ばにして
その時が来てしまう。
But before he could realize his dream,
time ran out.
六道仙人は　忍宗の力と意志を
２人の子供に託すことにした。
The Sage of the Six Paths decided to
entrust the power and will of the Ninshu
to his two children.
兄は　生まれながらに仙人の眼…→
The older son was born with
the Sage's eyes.
チャクラと精神エネルギーを授かり→
He inherited the Sage's chakra
and mental energy,
平和には　力が必要だと悟った。
and believed that strength
was crucial to peace.
弟は　生まれながらに仙人の肉体。
The younger son was born with
the gift of the Sage's body.
生命力と身体エネルギーを授かり→
He inherited the Sage's life force
and physical energy,
平和には　愛が必要だと悟った。
and believed that love was
crucial to peace.
仙人は最後　死の床で後継者を
決めなければならなかった。
Ultimately, the Sage was forced to choose
his successor from his deathbed.
しかし　その決断が　永劫続く
憎しみの呪いを生んでしまった。
However, his decision
created a curse of hatred that
has continued for generations.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean by that?
仙人は　力を求めた兄ではなく
愛を求めた弟こそ→
Instead of his older son,
who sought strength,
the Sage felt that the younger son,
who sought love,
後継者にふさわしいと
そちらを選んだ。
was more suitable, and named him
as his successor.
長男として　当然　自分が
後継者だと思い込んでいた兄は→
The firstborn, who had long expected
to follow in his father's footsteps,
納得せず　憎しみのあまり
弟に争いを仕掛けた。
could not accept the decision.
Filled with rage,
he challenged his younger brother.
時が経ち　血が薄れても
２人の兄弟の子孫は争い続けた。
Even as time passed and
new generations were born,
the descendants of the two brothers,
continued to battle.
兄の子孫は　のちに
うちはと呼ばれ→
The descendants of the older brother,
came to be known as the Uchiha.
弟の子孫は　のちに
千手と呼ばれるようになる。
And the descendants of the younger brother
were called the Senju.
この　うちはマダラと
初代火影　千手柱間との戦いも→
As Madara Uchiha, my battle with
the First Hokage, Hashirama Senju,
運命だった。
was destined to take place.
お前と会うのは　まだ二度目だが→
This is only the second time I've met you.
千手の火の意志が
お前の中に宿っているのがわかる。
But I can tell that you hold
the Senju's Will of Fire within you.
今も　お前の中に
初代火影を見ることができる。
I can see the First Hokage inside you.
死んでも　なお
あいつは生き続けている。
Even after death, he lives on.
俺の憧れであり　ライバルであり→
He, whom I admired,
yet he was my rival.
俺の　もっとも憎んだ男。
And the man I hated most.
千手と　うちは。
The Senju and the Uchiha.
火の意志と憎しみ。
The Will of Fire and hatred.
ナルトとサスケ。　お前たち２人は→
Naruto and Sasuke.
You both will probably be
the next chosen by fate.
運命に選ばれた
次の２人になるだろう。
うちはは
復讐を運命づけられた一族。
The Uchiha was destined to
be a clan of vengeance.
サスケは　うちはの憎しみを
すべて背負い→
Sasuke has shouldered
the entire burden of the Uchiha's hatred
その憎しみの呪いを
世界へぶつけるつもりだ。
and intends to strike the world
with that curse.
もっとも強い武器であり
友であり　力である→
It is the most powerful weapon.
It's his friend and source of power,
this thing called hatred.
憎しみ。
それが　サスケの忍道だ！
And it is Sasuke's Ninja Way!
ano suiheisen ga touzakatte iku
Far beyond the horizon it continues
ao sugita sora ni wa ashita sura egake nakute
A sky so blue, you can't draw tomorrow
iki mo dekinai kurai yodonda hito no mure
It's stifling with crowds of people down here
boku wa itsukara koko ni moguri kondan da?
Just when did I dive into this?
kanashimi nante hakidashite mae dake mi tereba iin dakke?
Spit out sadness and keep looking ahead, right?
sore ja totemo matomo de irarenai
You can't stay true to yourself like that
subete o boku ga teki ni mawashite mo
Even if I turn against everything,
hikari o kasuka ni kanji terun da
I still feel glimmers of light
soko made yuke sou nara
If I could only reach it...
iki o shitakute koko wa kurushikute
I want to breathe, I'm suffocating here
yami o miageru dake no boku ja
Only looking up into the dark means,
ukabu houhou mo nai daibaa
I'm a diver who can't surface
iki o shite mite
Take a deep breath
tada no shiawase ni kizuitara mou nidoto oborenai yo
Discover joy, plain and simple and you'll never drown
Sasuke's Ninja Way
（サスケ）千鳥！
Chidori.
（エー）エルボウ！！
Elbow Bolt!
雷遁で
威力と貫通力を高めた突き攻撃。
A thrust attack using the Lightning Style
to increase force and penetration.
はたけカカシと同じ術か。
The same jutsu used
by Kakashi Hatake!
雷遁の鎧をまとった　このわしに
触れることができるとは…→
I wear Lightning Style armor,
yet you actually touched me.
たいした術だな。
That is some jutsu.
（水月）クソ　駄目か！
（ダルイ）ああ　駄目だな！
Damn it! It didn't work?!
No, it didn't.
あれで　サスケは死んだ！
Sasuke's dead.
《香燐：そんな…　こんなチャクラ…》
No way! Chakra like this...
やぁ～！！
ライガーボム！！
Liger Bomb!
終わったな。
It's over.
《あれが…　雷影の忍体術か。
So that's the Raikage's ninja taijutsu.
これでは
もう　サスケは　生きていまい。
Sasuke couldn't have survived that.
増援はいらなかったな》
We didn't need reinforcements.
Huh?
《あれが　万華鏡写輪眼か…》
So that's the Mangekyo Sharingan.
フン！
シー　大丈夫か？
ダルイ…。
Shee, you okay?
そっちは　ケリがついたのか？
かな…。
Darui... did you settle your fight?
あのライガーボムを食らって
生きてるやつなんて→
Maybe.
No one's ever lived through
that Liger Bomb, until now.
今までいなかった…
あの骨にしろ　何なんだ　こいつ。
Those bones and stuff...
What is he anyway?
俺が　幻術で押し負けた。
I fell for his genjutsu and lost.
体が　まだ
思うように動かない…。
I still don't have full control of my body.
ああいう天才は
たまに出てくる…。
Geniuses like him appear once in a while.
《うちはサスケ…　しぶとい…。
Sasuke Uchiha...
He's a stubborn one!
増援か！？》
Reinforcements?!
おい　シー…　うちはの眼
前と少し違わねえか？
Hey Shee... The Uchiha's eye...
Doesn't it seem a bit different
from before?
万華鏡写輪眼か！？
Mangekyo Sharingan?!
《そうか…　だから　雷影様は→
I get it. That's what made
Lord Raikage activate that much.
あそこまでの活性化を…。
瞬身の術で　対抗する気だ》
He intends to counter with
his Teleportation Jutsu.
ぬぁ～！
僕…　雷遁に弱すぎるかな？
Maybe I'm too weak against
the Lightning Style.
しびれて
上手く液体化もできやしない…。
My body's too numb and
can't liquefy properly.
《雷影のチャクラが
むちゃくちゃ　でかくなった。
Raikage's chakra has grown enormous.
これじゃ　尾獣並だぞ！》
He's at Tailed Beast levels!
来い　小僧！
Come on, brat!
《天照！》
Amaterasu!
ぐわぁ～！
うわぁ！
炎を消すんだ！
ただの炎じゃない　近づくな！
Put out the fire!
It's not ordinary fire!
Don't get close to it!
《見ている視点から発火する
天照！
Amaterasu, which ignites anything
in its line of sight.
これが…》
So this is it.
雷虐水平！
Lateral Bolt of Pain!
《上手い！　黒炎の盾！
Way to go!
A shield of Black Flames!
雷影の瞬身スピードはケタ違い。
Nothing can match
the Raikage's teleportation speed.
眼で　追いきれないなら
触れてはいけない盾にすればいい。
If you can't keep up visually,
then use a shield that can't be touched!
これで　迂闊に
サスケには攻撃できない》
Now, he won't be able to
carelessly attack Sasuke.
《黒炎をコントロールしたのか！？
He's manipulating the Black Flames?!
形態変化まで…。
He can even change
their chakra form!
イタチよりも
黒炎に長けているというのか？》
Don't tell me he's more proficient
with the Black Flames than Itachi?
雷影をなめるな！
Don't underestimate the Raikage!
雷影様！　まさか…。
Lord Raikage! Impossible...
左腕をくれてやるとはね…。
He's sacrificing his left arm.
とどめだ！
You're finished!
ギロチンドロップ！
Guillotine Drop!
炎遁　カグツチ！
《あいつ　まだ…》
Inferno Style: Flame Control!
《サスケ！》
He's still in the air!
Sasuke!
《砂！》
《これは…》
Sand!
This is...
砂漠の　我愛羅…。
Gaara of the Sand.
（テマリ）鎌いたちの術！
Wind Scythe Jutsu!
（カンクロウ）これが消えない炎…
天照ってやつか。
So these are the flames
that never burn out, Amaterasu, huh?
（我愛羅）侍たちは下がっていろ。
これは忍の世界のゴタゴタだ。
You Samurai, get back.
This is a problem for the ninja world.
あんたたち　侍が
犠牲になることはない。
There is no need for Samurai
to become casualties.
す…　すまない　風影殿。
うっ…。
Th-Thank you, Lord Kazekage.
どうなってんだろ？
なぜ　邪魔をした！？　風影。
What's going on?
Why did you interfere, Kazekage?!
返答次第では　許さんぞ！
Whether I punish you or not
depends on your answer!
あのまま　あんたが技を出せば→
If you had continued and
performed another attack,
黒煙で更に
体を傷つけることになった。
the Black Flames would
have further injured you.
それに　うちはサスケには
話したいことがある。
Besides, I wish to speak
to Sasuke Uchiha.
ボス！
シー　早く止血しろ！
Boss!
Shee, hurry and stop the bleeding!
でき次第　サスケを叩く！
はっ。
I'm going to attack Sasuke
the minute you're done.
Yes sir!
《雷遁の鎧をまとった
雷影様に触ることができ→
Sasuke was able to lay
a hand on Lord Raikage,
who was clad in
his Lightning Style armor.
２つの大技を食らっても
まだ生きている。
And he's still alive despite
two heavy attacks.
左目は天照。
Amaterasu in his left eye.
右目は　その天照の黒煙を→
And in his right eye,
形態変化させる能力とみて
間違いないだろう》
he has the ability to change the
chakra form of Amaterasu's Black Flames,
there's no mistake.
《本当にビーは　このサスケに
捕まったのかもしれない…》
Perhaps Sasuke captured Bee after all.
《忍の世界
まだ先があるというのか》
Does that mean there's still progress
occurring in the ninja world?
お前の目は昔のままだな。
Your eyes are still as they were
in the past.
((言ったはずだ
お前は俺と同じ目をしていると。
I once told you that you
have eyes like mine.
力を求め憎しみと
殺意に満ちている目。
Eyes that seek strength.
Eyes overflowing with hate
and a hunger for blood.
己を孤独という地獄に
追い込んだ者を→
Eyes itching to kill the one who threw you
into the hell called solitude.
(殺したくて
うずうずしている目だ))
復讐を生きる糧としても→
Making revenge your sustenance
resolves nothing.
何も解決はしないことを
俺は実感してきた。
I learned that lesson personally.
お前なら　まだ間に合う。
It's not too late for you.
憎しみに取り憑かれ
１人の世界に逃げ込むな。
Do not cast yourself into a world where
you are all alone, obsessed with hate.
帰ってこられなくなるぞ。
You won't be able to return.
で　俺が帰ったとして
そっちには何がある？
And if I returned?
What would I find there?
我愛羅やめとけ。
Forget it, Gaara.
説得できるなら
ナルトは失敗してねえじゃん。
Naruto already failed at convincing him.
こいつは今や
暁にまで落ちた犯罪者だ。
He's just a criminal now,
who has fallen to the level
of the Akatsuki.
お前とは違う。
それに雷影や→
He's not like you.
Besides, neither the Raikage
nor the others
暁にやられた者たちも
黙ってはいない。
who have been victimized by
the Akatsuki will remain silent.
五影会談を襲撃した時点で
国際手配される。
After attacking the Five Kage Summit,
he's now wanted internationally.
どの道　こいつに未来はない。
This guy has no future.
サスケ　お前は俺と似ている。
Sasuke, you and I are alike.
この世の闇を歩いてきた者…。
We've both walked through
the darkness of this world.
だからこそ　小さな光明ですら
目に届くはずだ。
That's why you should be able to see
even the faintest glimmer of light.
昔も　そして今も…。
In the past and even now.
俺は　とっくに目を閉じた。
I closed my eyes long ago.
俺の目的は闇の中にしかない。
My goals exist only in the darkness.
私情を挟むな　お前は風影だぞ。
Leave your personal feelings
out of this.
You are the Kazekage.
《我愛羅…》
Gaara...
あぁ。
I know.
わかっている。
I understand.
ナルト　お前はいずれ
サスケと戦うことになるだろう。
Naruto...
You will probably end up
fighting Sasuke one day.
いや　俺がお前にサスケをぶつける。
Rather... I will throw Sasuke at you.
長きにわたる因縁の戦い。
A battle that was predestined ages ago.
うちはの存在をサスケに証明させる。
I'll have Sasuke validate
the existence of the Uchiha.
サスケは　おめえのオモチャじゃねえ！
勝手なこと言ってんな！
Sasuke isn't your toy!
Quit making selfish plans!
サスケも長門のように
心変わりさせてやるとでも？
You think you can make Sasuke
have a change of heart,
like you did with Nagato?
それこそ勝手な言い分だぞ　ナルト。
That's just as selfish, Naruto.
人をコントロールするには→
Controlling people requires the skill to
manipulate the darkness in their souls.
心の闇を利用するテクニックが必要だ。
長門は　たまたま
人に感化されやすい子だったがな。
Although, Nagato just happened to
be easily influenced by others.
長門とてめえを一緒にすんな。
Don't liken Nagato to yourself!
やり方は　違ってもあいつは
本心で平和を望んでた。
His ways were different,
but he truly wished for peace!
けど　おめえは違う！
But you're different!
フッ　だな。
You're right.
うちはの存在　くだらない
その証明が目的なら→
The existence of the Uchiha...
If that's all you want to validate,
why hunt the Tailed Beasts?
なぜ　尾獣を集める？
お前の目的は　いったい何だ？
何が望みなんだ？
Just what is your goal?
What do you hope to accomplish?
そうだな　しいて言うなら→
Let's see...
If anything, it's to become complete.
完全体になることか。
完全体？
どういうことだ？
Complete?!
What do you mean?!
お前らに話しても
あまり意味がない。
Talking to you is meaningless.
もっと効果的な場で話す。
I'll explain more
in an appropriate place.
お前らとの会話　楽しかったよ。
じゃあな。
Our conversation... was quite fun.
So long.
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
炎遁をここまで
ガードされるとは。
I'm impressed that you can guard
against my Inferno Style so effectively.
絶対防御は　健在だな。
Your Ultimate Defense is
in good shape.
（黒ツチ）すげぇ！
A-Amazing.
（香燐）見つけた！　ダンゾウもいる！
Found them! Danzo's among them!
《すぐに　サスケに知らせねえと。
I must notify Sasuke immediately!
しかし　あたりは
強ぇチャクラばっかだな》
But... there's powerful chakra all around.
《フー：やはり　感知タイプがいたか》
So there's a Sensory-Type after all.
どうやら　敵には
感知タイプがいるようです。
It seems the enemy has
a Sensory-Type ninja.
いずれ　ここに
来るかもしれませんがどのように。
They may come here in time.
（ダンゾウ）このままでいい。
そいつらが来たら→
What do we do?
Nothing for now.
その混乱に乗じて外へ出る。
When they arrive,
we'll slip out during the chaos.
（青）コソコソ話すのはやめろ。
Stop whispering over there!
（青）悪いが　俺も感知タイプだ。
Sorry, but I'm a Sensory-Type too.
敵に　ここがバレたのも
わかってる。
I'm fully aware that the enemy is on to us.
だが　あんたたちは
決して動くな。
But you are not to make a move.
敵は　こちらで対処する。
We'll deal with the enemy.
《オオノキ：この会談も
おもしろくなりそうじゃぜ》
It seems this summit is about
to become very interesting.
まだか　シー！
もう少しです。
Are you done yet, Shee?!
Just a little longer.
協力する　砂の衆！
初弾は俺が！
Comrades of the Hidden Sand!
I will fire the first shot!
続けて　たたみかけをお願いする。
よし。
Press ahead after me!
嵐遁　レイザーサーカス！
Right!
Gale Style: Laser Circus!
赤秘技　機々三角！
Secret Red Move: Puppet Triad!
大鎌いたち！
Cyclone Scythe Jutsu!
連弾　砂時雨！
Sand Shower Barrage!
《サスケ！》
Sasuke!
《こ…　これって！》
W-What is this?!
我愛羅…　お前以上の
絶対防御だ。
Gaara... This is even greater than
your Ultimate Defense.
わしの攻撃を
ガードしていたのもあれか。
Did he use that to guard
against my attacks?
《このチャクラ…
あのときの幻術と同じ》
This chakra...
It's the same as that genjutsu earlier.
なんか　やばそうだな。
This doesn't look good.
《試したかったってのはこれか》
Was this what he wanted to test?
《このチャクラ…
もう前のサスケじゃねえ。
This chakra...
He's no longer the old Sasuke.
冷たすぎる》
It's too cold.
何だあれは？
What is that?
闇の力か…。
The power... of darkness?
両眼の万華鏡を
開眼した者だけが手にする力→
A power that only those
who have awakened the Mangekyo
in both eyes can achieve.
第三の力…　スサノオだ。
This is the third power...
Susano'o.
mayonaka no utaga sakenda
The poetry of midnight cries out,
boku hontou wa ano hi kara zutto
"Ever since that day, I actually..."
akaku sukitooru yuugure no ato
After the twilight in hues of red,
hoshi tachi wa sora ni tsuwari sorezore no oto kanadeteitta
Stars sit on the sky, Each making their own sound
sunao ni nare to iware nakutemo
You don't need to tell me to be true to myself
namida wa mo boku no omoi tsurete
My tears have already taken my feelings
ashi moto de chiisana umi ni natta
and formed a small ocean at my feet
sora wa ugokanai higa nobori oriru dake
The sky is still. Only the sun rises and sets
jimen wa ugokanai kimi ga arukuka arukanaika dake da
The ground is still. It's up to you to take a step or not
mayonaka no uta ga sakenda
The poetry of midnight cries out,
boku hontou wa hitori ga kirai da
"I actually hate being alone. I hate it"
dai kirai da taisetsu wo shitte shimatta ano hi kara zutto
Since that day I learned what was important
aa shiawase nante chiisana spoon de tsukueru kurai de
A small spoonful of happiness is more than enough
jyuubun nanda wakeaeru hito ga iruka inaika dake da
It's just whether you have someone to share it with or not
Next Episode
もしもし？　そこの　あなた。
When I look at you closely,
たまには　空から日本を→
you of the Uchiha Clan are quite handsome.
Don't interfere!
眺めてみるというのは
どうじゃろう？
Such a fine man. What a waste.
今回は　環状七号線じゃ。
I'll at least give you a kiss that will make you melt.
通称　環七通り！
Lady Mizukage is intent on fighting!
東京の大動脈には
不思議な景色が　いっぱいじゃ！
Lord Tsuchikage, if you're not going to participate,
please keep your head lowered.
わっ　家がくっついてます！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Power of the Five Kage"
Power of the Five Kage
では　そろそろ出発じゃ。
Feel free to rampage as you please.